<models>
 <model>
    <id>Model1</id>
    <title>Ravenstein&apos;s Gravity Model</title>
    <image>models/gravity.jpg</image>
    <description>Ernst Ravenstein developed the &lt;strong&gt;Gravity Model&lt;/strong&gt;. The Gravity Model predicts the interaction between two places based on the size of their populations and the distance between them. This model assumes that spatial interaction is directly linked to the populations and indirectly linked to the distance between the two places. There is a math equation that goes with the Gravity Model: multiply the two populations together and then divide by the distance between them. This equations shows how often they interact with each other.</description>
 </model>
 <model>
    <id>Model2</id>
    <title>Hierarchical Diffusion</title>
    <description>The idea or product is passed on first to the most connected cities.</description>
 </model>
 <model>
    <id>Model3</id>
    <title>Contagious Diffusion</title>
    <description>The idea or product is spread from person to person as if it was a disease.</description>
 </model>
 <model>
    <id>Model4</id>
    <title>Distance Decay</title>
    <image>models/distanceDecay.jpg</image>
    <description>&lt;strong&gt;Distance decay&lt;/strong&gt; is the idea that the farther two groups of people are away from each other, the communication between them decreases. Distance decay is commonly shown on a graph. One axis is labeled amount of interaction intensity, and the other axis is labeled increasing distance. At the top of the graph is &quot;very high interaction.&quot; This means the distance between the two groups is small. Under &quot;very high interaction&quot; is &quot;high interaction.&quot; The distance line shows the distance between the two groups is a little bigger. As you go down the graph, there becomes less interaction and a larger distance between the two groups.</description>
 </model>
 <model>
    <id>Model5</id>
    <title>Time-space Compression</title>
    <description>David Harvey explains how the movement of product and ideas has increased since the improvement of transportation and communication.</description>
 </model>
 <model>
    <id>Model6</id>
    <title>Epidemiological Transition Model</title>
    <image>models/epidemiological.jpg</image>
    <description>The &lt;strong&gt;Epidemiological Transition Model&lt;/strong&gt; shows the cause of death in each of the stages in the Demographic Transition Model. The first stage was developed by Abdel Omran in 1971. It has been modified to 4 main stages and a possible fifth stage. The Black Plaque was the major cause of death in Stage 1. It killed 25 million Europeans from 1347 to 1350, and the Black Plaque killed 13 million Chinese in 1380. Cholera, an infection in the small intestine, was a major epidemic in the time of the Industrial Revolution. This was the major epidemic in Stage 2. It killed about three thousand five hundred people in New York City in 1832, and it wiped out about thirty six thousand in Cairo in 1831. In Stage 3, the major cause of death was infectious diseases and chronic disorders associated with aging, such as cardiovascular diseases and cancer. Infectious diseases have started to decline sharply in Stage 3 countries. Stage 4 is characterized by cardiovascular diseases and cancer. Medical advances have extended the life expectancy of older people. The growth of cancer can now be slowed down or removed all together. There is a possible Stage 5 that is characterized by infectious diseases and parasitic diseases.</description>
 </model>
 <model>
    <id>Model7</id>
    <title>Population Pyramid</title>
    <image>models/populationPyramid.jpg</image>
    <description>&lt;strong&gt;Population pyramids&lt;/strong&gt; show the age distribution and sex ratio of a specific population. They present the percentage of each age group in the entire population. Each age group is called a cohort. By looking at a country&apos;s population pyramid, you can tell how wealthy a country is and what stage of the DTM it is in. The key is to look at birth and death rates. In poorer countries, the birth and death rates are usually high. If there is a large amount of children and a small amount of elderly people, the country is usually less developed. In a wealthier country, the birth and death rates are low. If there is an almost equal percentage of children and elderly people, the country is usually more developed.</description>
 </model>
 <model>
    <id>Model8</id>
    <title>Core/Periphery Model (World Systems Theory)</title>
    <image>models/corePeriphery.jpg</image>
    <description>The world economy is a three-tier structure: the core, the periphery, and semi-periphery. Core processes incorporate higher levels of education and include higher wages and more technology. There processes develop more wealth in the global economy. On the contrary, periphery processes include the lower levels of education and incorporate lower salaries and less technology. Semi-peripheries, as you can imagine, are simply a buffer between the two extremes of core and periphery. This process generally includes the exploitation of the periphery by the core. Although these are processes, they occur in places and are sometimes assigned to states. For example, the US and Canada are core states while Chile and Iraq are periphery.</description>
 </model>
 <model>
    <id>Model9</id>
    <title>Demographic Transition Model</title>
    <image>models/demographicTransition.jpg</image>
    <description>The &lt;strong&gt;Demographic Transition Model&lt;/strong&gt; (DTM) was developed in 1929 by Warren Thompson. It has four main stages. Stage 1 is low growth, Stage 2 is high growth, Stage 3 is moderate growth, and Stage 4 is low growth. In Stage 1, the crude birth rates (CBR) and the crude death rates (CDR) are equally high. The Bubonic Plaque marks Stage 1 because of its high CDR. There are no countries currently in Stage 1. In Stage 2, the CBR is high, but the CDR is declining. During the late 1700s-early 1800s, the world population increased greatly. This was also the time of the Industrial Revolution. In Stage 3, the CDR still decline but much slower. The CBR sharply starts to decline. Most countries in Europe and North America enter Stage 3 in the early 1900s. The world&apos;s population still grew, but it grew at a much slower rate. In Stage 4, both the CBR and the CDR are low. Stage 4 also signifies women becoming more educated and entering the work force. Depending on the version of the DTM you look at, there may or may not be a fifth stage. Though not an official stage, it is still possible. In Stage 5, the CBR and the CDR are equally low. This signifies zero growth.</description>
 </model>
 <model>
    <id>Model10</id>
    <title>Rostow&apos;s Model of Development</title>
    <description>Walt Rostow&apos;s Ladder of Development model, also called the modernization model, shows the steps of development in countries. His model has to assume that all countries develop the same. There are five stages of development in this model. The first stage is called traditional. The main activity in countries at this stage is subsistence farming. These countries have a rigid social structure. The people of the country often refuse technological change. The second stage is called preconditions of takeoff. In this stage, there is a new leadership that moves the country towards diversity and flexibility. It prepares the country for the next stage. The third stage is called takeoff. During this stage, the country goes through something similar to an industrial revolution. Urbanization and industrialization start to occur. Improvements in technology and productions start to happen. The economy then enters the fourth stage called drive to maturity. During this stage, modernization starts to spark in important parts of the country. New technologies begin to diffuse, and industrial specialization starts up throughout the nation. Also, the population growth rate starts to slow. Only some countries reach the fifth stage. This stage is characterized by higher worker incomes and a widespread production of goods and services. The service industry develops greatly. Much of the country&apos;s workforce will be concentrated in the service sector. Rostow&apos;s model has received criticisms just like other development models. The problem with his model is it doesn&apos;t provide any context to development.</description>
 </model>
 <model>
    <id>Model11</id>
    <title>L&#246;sch&apos;s Model</title>
    <description>In 1967, August L&#246;sch wanted to determine the where the best sites for building manufacturing plants were in order to maximize profit. He added the influence of consumer demands and production costs to his calculations. Businesses usually locate themselves in an area where the can make a profit. This is how L&#246;sch&apos;s model works. He said the ideal place for a manufacturing plant would be in an area where production and transportation costs were low and income is high.</description>
 </model>
 <model>
    <id>Model12</id>
    <title>Hotelling&apos;s Model</title>
    <description>Harold Hotelling created the locational interdependence model. It states that two business competitors will try to take away from each other&apos;s territories in order to maximize sales. This would eventually result in the two businesses selling their products across from each other. To explain this, Hotelling used two ice cream vendors selling ice cream on a beach. They both start by selling at opposite ends of the beach. After a while, both vendors try to maximize their sales by moving closer to the customers at the middle of the beach. Eventually, these vendors end up selling across from each other. The whole point of Hotelling&apos;s analysis was to show that the location of a business cannot be fully understood until it is referenced with the location of other businesses just like it.</description>
 </model>
 <model>
    <id>Model13</id>
    <title>Weber&apos;s Model</title>
    <description>Alfred Weber, a German economic geographer, developed a model for the ideal location of a business. His model was called the &lt;strong&gt;Least Cost Theory&lt;/strong&gt;. The Least Cost Theory finds the ideal location of a business by using three categories of costs that would minimize costs. These categories are transportation, labor, and agglomeration. The first category is transportation. The location had to result in the lowest possible cost of shipping raw materials to the manufacturing plant and the finished goods to the market. The second category is labor. Putting a business in an area where labor is cheap is ideal. If the business is put far from the resource location, the low cost of labor would make up for the transportation costs. The third category is agglomeration. Agglomeration is when many businesses are clustered in one area. This saves money because the equipment and furniture one company needs can be made by another company in the same area. The costs of transportation is greatly cut down.</description>
 </model>
 <model>
    <id>Model14</id>
    <title>Central Place Theory</title>
    <description>The &lt;strong&gt;central place theory&lt;/strong&gt; was created by &lt;strong&gt;Walter Christaller&lt;/strong&gt;. This model predicts how and where central places in the urban hierarchy (cities to villages) would be distributed based on their function and placement. The model is based on a few assumptions. The first is that the surface of the ideal region would be flat with no physical barriers, such as mountains or rivers. Secondly, that the soil fertility would be universal, so agriculture could take place anywhere in the city. Third, population and purchasing power would be evenly distributed. Next, transportation would be uniform and be available from one region to the next. Finally, any good or service could be sold anywhere and in every direction out to a certain distance. The model is set up so the largest central place would provide the most functions to the majority of the region. His model isn&apos;t circular, but actually a collection of hexagons that fit perfectly together. You can see an example of Christaller&apos;s model in the &lt;strong&gt;Sunbelt phenomenon&lt;/strong&gt; in southern regions.</description>
 </model>
 <model>
    <id>Model15</id>
    <title>House Structures</title>
    <description>The architecture of homes vary as they are scattered across different locations in different environments. For example, most New England Homes have the chimney in the center as to warm the house as a whole. The Middle Atlantic has a warmer climate, therefore the chimney is at only one end of the house. Southern houses are raised off the ground to cool the interior.</description>
 </model>
 <model>
    <id>Model16</id>
    <title>Sector Model</title>
    <description>The sector model was created by Homer Hoyt in the late 1930s. It serves as an evolved model from the concentric zone model, surpassing the limits of Burgess&apos;s. This model focuses on residential patterns to explain where the wealthy in a city choose to live. Hoyt developed this model like pie, with each slice representing a different residential area, education and recreation, transportation, and industrial sectors. The focal point of the city is the core, where the other sectors grow outward.</description>
 </model>
 <model>
    <id>Model17</id>
    <title>Multiple Nuclei Model</title>
    <description>Chauncy Harris and Edward Ullman created the multiple nuclei model in the 1940s on the basis that neither the concentric zone or sector model adequately reflect mid-twentieth century cities. The theme of their model is that the CBD is losing its dominancy as the single core of a city.</description>
 </model>
</models>
